AHMED FAYYAZ

ReactNative Developer | Technical Team Lead

+923066808743 • ahmedfayyaz1995@qmail.com • http://linkedin.com/in/ahmed-fayyaz-dev • Lahore, Pakistan

Summary

A seasoned react native developer having over 5 years experience in Mobile App Development. Involved in diverse roles such as Team Lead, Product Manager, testing, development. Shipped to production over 25 ERP, Logistics & Tracking, Fitness Applications, Chat, Al-based and many more applications.

Strong command on frontend development with exposure to programming, code-architect, debugging, UI/UX and CI/CD pipelines.

Experience

TxLabz Lahore, Pakistan

Team Lead | Senior Software Engineer

08/2023 - Present

- Leading a team of React Native developers (~10) across multiple projects
- Developed and shipped applications in various domains (Chatting, gaming, Services providing, Payments, Social)
- · Involved in onboarding clients for giving technical interviews and discussing ideas (70% success rate)
- Conducted monthly workshops for team to improve coding skills/quality, discussing new tools/libs (observed 20% performance gains)
- · Co-ordinated with UI/UX designers to create a common components-ui sdk to jump start and acceleraate the development flow
- · Adapting Multiple roles based on requirements and priorities (Project Management/QA Testing/etc)
- · Code reviews and Mentoring

Zeta Enterprises Pvt. Ltd. https

Lahore, Pakistan

Senior Software Engineer | Team Lead

06/2021 - 07/2023

- Leading a small team of React Native developers and mentoring them on best practices, code quality, and performance optimization
- Ensuring clean, reusable, and scalable code, following best practices and coding standards
- · Shipped products for e-commerce, Drop-shipping clients such as ERP, Inventory managements, CO, Warehouse Operations

Awkits Lahore, Pakistan

Software Engineer

02/2022 - 08/2022

- · Transitioning existing React web apps to React Native and maintaining code consistency across platforms
- Responsible for developing mobile end apps of ongoing ecommerce project (Food and grocery delivery app) including rider, customer, and vendor
- Developed smooth checkout flow, Delivery statuses, Rider Live Location, Map Direction for destination
- · Covering the maintenance of react/nextjs web projects

Hostollo Inc Lahore, Pakistan

Software Engineer

06/2019 - 05/2021

- Creating smooth and user friendly mobile apps using reactnative and Android
- Collaborating with project managers, designers, and other developers to deliver high-quality products that meet the client's requirements and expectations
- · Communicating with clients and team on slack and tracking/updating Tasks on Jira/trello

Projects

Aura App

Management At your fingertips GENETWORx Laboratory's unique software platform. Aura provides employers with an easy tool for scheduling, receiving, and managing test results

- Link
- React native | Typescript

myChat

myChat is an end-to-end encrypted chat app with WhatsApp like chat and call experience.

- AppStore Link, Playstore Link
- React native | Typescript | SocketIO | Agora

Powered by Enhancy

Projects

MoodMe

Relationship care - made simple

- · AppStore Link, Playstore Link
- React native | In App Purchases | Crashlytics | Firebase analytics

ASPCL - Ajman Sewerage

At ASPCL, our non-profit Community Care Foundation In line with our strategic goals, we aim to educate the community about water consumption and waste management in Ajman.

- Link
- React Native

Travelo - Al Travel Planner

Travelo leverages cutting-edge GPT technology to offer personalised travel ideas and advice

- Link
- React native | firestore | openAi

Auraya wallet

Non custodial Crypto exchange wallet built by leveraging magic-link sdk

• React native | MagicLink | Ethereum

Rivalog

Logistics operations, increases your profit, reduces time loss and freight cost.

- LINK
- Google Maps | Location Tracking | Forms | Vehicle buy n sell

Wits

WITS is an online multiplayer quiz application with topics that you are master at! Play with your friends or anonymous people around the globe - in both cases you have the chance to have a lot of fun.

- AppStore Link, Playstore link
- React native | LiveKit | Socket io

Skills

React Native · Expo · Node Js · Express · Firebase · AWS Cognito · Stripe · Redux JS · MOBX Lite · Zustand · React Query (@tanstack Query) · SOCKET IO · Agora · MapBox · Google Maps · Github · Github Actions · CI/CD · XCode · Android Studio · Appstore · Playstore · Husky · Eslint

Education

University of Management and Technology

Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor - Computer Science

01/2017 - 06/2021